flightnetwork.com 2019-11-12

# Terms & Conditions - FlightNetwork.com

## Terms & Conditions

By completing a transaction with FlightNetwork, you have agreed to the following Terms & Conditions listed below: 

  *     * 24-Hr Free Cancellation

Free 24-hr cancellation is indicated at the time of booking and only provided to particular reservations made seven days or more prior to the flights scheduled departure dates. When free 24-hr cancellation is provided, your flight is eligible for cancellation up until 24 hours after the time of booking. When cancelled outside of 24 hours, standard cancellation fees will apply. 

    * AirHelp+

By purchasing the AirHelp+ product, you’ve agreed that AirHelp+, a 3rd party company, will fight for the protection of your passenger rights in the event of an airline cancellation or delay. (Note: This is different than trip cancellation insurance where if purchased, flights can be cancelled before the passengers travel date.) If all passengers are ready to fly however, there is an airline initiated cancellation or delay, passengers could be awarded cash compensation. AirHelp+ will facilitate the process of getting money back for you. At the time of flight departure AirHelp+ is provided with your airline booking ID number, the number of passengers travelling, your itinerary details and the email address provided at the time of booking. If/when your booking is eligible, you will receive instant notification via email to the email address provided at the time of booking. In the event of a voluntary cancellation, this AirHelp+ service is non-refundable. If you have any questions please feel free to contact us at any of the numbers provided [here](https://www.flightnetwork.com/pages/about-us). Alternatively, you can visit the full AirHelp+ Terms & Conditions [here](https://www.airhelp.com/en-gb/terms/). 

    * Automatic Online Check-in

By purchasing the Automatic Check-in Product, you’ve agreed to allow us to check-in all parties on your booking and have your boarding pass issued automatically and sent to your registered email address no later than 3 hours prior to departure. We advise you to print these before travelling as some airlines may charge a fee to print them at the airport. You’ve agreed that you will NOT travel with any dangerous goods in your carry-on or on you. This applies to all passengers on the booking. Dangerous goods include but are not limited to: explosives, inflammable liquids. gases, solids and oxidizing agents, magnetic, radioactive and/or corrosive materials – for instance colours, fireworks, teargas, quicksilver, lighter fluid and radiopharmaceuticals. NOTE: As this information is subject to change at any time, we always recommend you visit the website of the issuing airline and double-check for accuracy. We cannot guarantee that your entire travel party will be seated together. In the event of a voluntary cancellation, this Automatic Online Check in ancillary service is non-refundable. If we require more information to check in all parties, we will reach out to you via email. For example, passport numbers may be required for online check-in which may or may not be asked of you during the booking process. If you have any questions please feel free to contact us at any of the numbers provided [here](https://help.flightnetwork.com/customer/portal/emails/new). 

    * Baggage Terms

### Baggage Allowance and Restrictions

Baggage fees are not included in the cost of your ticket unless permitted by the airline. Baggage allowance varies from airline to airline and can also vary based on the class of service purchased (I.e. not all economy class tickets offer free baggage allowance). Some airlines charge additional fees for both; check-in and carry-on baggage. Some airlines charge additional fees for adding baggage to the reservation at the airport or after you’ve completed your purchase online. We strongly suggest that baggage is added in advance for such carriers. Moreover; it is the passengers responsibility to check any baggage rules with the airline before making a purchase on our website as Flight Network has zero control over the airline’s ever-changing baggage policies. If you are not sure about a baggage policy, please contact Flight Network prior to booking in order to verify the specific airlines details. Flight Network charges a nominal service charge to add baggage to your booking, you will be notified of the amount at time of purchase. During the booking process, we will only display Economy, Premium Economy, Business or First Class of service types. Many airlines offer branded fare options within these four classes of service (For example: Basic Economy or Flex Economy). We may display a fare as Economy Class even though it is Basic Economy. Since our website is not able to accommodate these branded fare types, we will only list the main classes of service during the purchase process. If you are unsure of the branded fare type within your class of service, please contact us prior to completing your booking so that we can validate the full baggage terms for you. There is a rare chance that your ticket may involve two carriers that do not have ticketing agreements with one another. This means that your baggage will not be checked through to your final destination. In such cases, you will need to collect your baggage and recheck in and this may result in additional baggage charges. Please verify the minimum connection time and baggage information with the airlines directly before your departure. Airlines that do not have ticketing agreements are usually labeled on the Flight Network website as ‘Self-Transfer’ fares. Any baggage purchased at the time of booking is 100% non-refundable. Get the most up-to-date [baggage information](https://www.flightnetwork.com/pages/airline-information/) here. 

    * Baggage Loss Protection Terms

### Baggage Loss Protection:

In the event that the airline loses your baggage, this program covers the amount disclosed during the checkout process (per passenger) in addition to any compensation received from the airline or private insurance company. Baggage Loss Protection is not an insurance product. 

    * Best Purchase Guarantee Terms

### Best Purchase Guarantee Terms:

Purchasing Best Purchase Guarantee Protection allows you to cancel your booking on the same day it was made, without any cancellation fees, up until 11:59PM EST (Ontario, Canada Time). The cost to add this feature varies by airline, destination and the type of fare purchased and is outlined prior to booking completion. To utilize Best Purchase Guarantee and cancel your booking you must call us at any of the numbers listed on our website. [link to: https://www.flightnetwork.com/pages/about-us] Cancellations over email will not be accepted. Best Purchase Guarantee can also be purchased AFTER a flight booking has been made however, it must be a booking made on that same day, before 11:59 pm EST. This product does not apply to flight changes. If you require a change to your flight(s), change fees by the airline and Flight Network may be applied as well as any difference in the fare for the new itinerary selected. If Best Purchase Guarantee Protection is selected, it must be applied to all passengers on the itinerary. Important: Be mindful of the time that you are purchasing Best Purchase Guarantee in your local country as it relates to Ontario, Canada time. 

    * Booking Confirmation by Text Message (SMS)

By purchasing the Booking Confirmation by Text (SMS) Product, you’ve agreed to receive a text message with your booking reference number(s) to make it easy for you to contact us or the airline directly at any time. You will receive an SMS immediately after booking which will be sent to the mobile number provided at the time of booking. Please do not reply to this text as it is not monitored. Your regular carrier fees may apply. In the event of a voluntary cancellation, this SMS ancillary service is non-refundable. In the event that you enter an incorrect mobile number at the time of booking this message may not be able to be resent. If you have any questions please feel free to contact us at any of the numbers provided here. [here](https://help.flightnetwork.com/customer/portal/emails/new)

    * Canada’s New Electronic Travel Authorization (eTA)

Effective November 10, 2016, visa-exempt foreign nationals must obtain an eTA before they can board a flight to Canada. To complete their application for an eTA, customers will need a valid passport, a credit card and an email address. An eTA costs $7 CAD and is valid for up to five years or until your passport expires (whichever comes first). *Visa-exempt foreign nationals are persons who are not citizens of Canada and are not required to obtain a visa for the purpose of travel based on their country of nationality. Please refer to [ http://www.cic.gc.ca/english/visit/visas.asp](http://www.cic.gc.ca/english/visit/visas.asp). This eTA is required to be obtained prior to boarding. 

    * Cartagena (Colombian Entry Tax)

All Canadians are required to pay the new “Reciprocity Fee” of approximately 171,000 Pesos ($72 CAD) upon entry at either airports or seaports in Colombia. The fee is for single entry of individuals between the ages of 14 and 79. The payment can only be made in Colombian Pesos, US Dollars or via credit card. The fee does not guarantee entry to Colombia and won’t be reimbursed. 

    * Changes (Cancellation, Name, Schedule) Terms

### Fares:

Most fares are discounted fares which may have cancellation and change penalties. Many of our fares may allow changes by collecting applicable penalties and a fare difference. Most fares can be canceled for a refund or a future time limited travel credit by collecting the applicable penalties and fare differences. All cancellations must be made prior to the scheduled departure time of the first flight segment. Airport fees, where applicable, are not included and are subject to change without prior notice. All prices are in Canadian dollars unless otherwise stated. All prices displayed on our website are subject to change prior to ticket issuance. Increased change in pricing quoted at time of booking to time of ticket issuance shall entitle the customer to cancel the booking and obtain a full refund. 

### Airline Schedule Changes:

If FlightNetwork® is aware of a change; every effort will be made to advise you directly. Please ensure you contact your airline at least 24-48 hours prior to departure and to be safe, again on the day of departure. It will be your responsibility to reconfirm all your flight details before departure. If there has been a last minute change by your Airline directly (within 48 hours) it is no longer the responsibility of Flight Network to notify you, it is the responsibility of your operating Airline. This is mandated under TICO (The Travel Industry Council of Ontario) and why it is also suggested to reconfirm flights prior to departure. You should always be at the airport 3 hours prior to departure to ensure that you arrive on time for check-in and not miss your flight. All affected schedule changes imposed by the Airlines will be notified by email. Any minor changes less than 30 minutes or with flight number changes will be automatically accepted on your behalf. Any changes 30 minutes to three hours prior or later from the original departure time(if it conflicts with another confirmed ticket itinerary schedule); passengers will be given an option to modify the flight times within 5 days of receiving the schedule change by email. This modification must be with the same carrier, in the same cabin for first available flight. These modifications can only be performed within the airline’s schedule change rebooking guidelines and cannot be guaranteed. Any voluntary changes are subject to the carrier’s normal change or cancellation penalties. If not acknowledged within 5 days from the receipt of the email communication, Flight Network will accept it on behalf of the passengers. We cannot guarantee that the airline will allow modification after the ticket has been reissued or revalidated by the airline. Any major schedule changes beyond three hours from the original departure times; we will send an email notification followed by a phone call to review the affected schedule change. Schedule changes delayed or advanced by 24 hours or more are subject to the next available flight or a full refund. We will not be responsible if the customer fails to enter the correct email and/or phone information at time of reservation. All schedule changes are mandated by airlines directly. Airlines reserve the right to change, cancel or refund based on adjustments to their flight schedules. Flight Network assumes no responsibility for airline schedule changes, however we will do our best to provide alternate travel options if available. 

### Package/Charter Schedule Changes:

The Airline reserves the right to change flight times within the same day and to include a stop in the flight, not part of the original itinerary with no option for cancellation or compensation. Please read information below regarding the procedure for ANY CHARTER AIRLINE FLIGHT SCHEDULE CHANGE. Any flight that departs: 0-59 minutes earlier, no notification will be provided, please check with your local airport. If FlightNetwork® is aware of a change; every effort will be made to advise you directly. Please ensure you contact your airline at least 24 hours prior to departure and on the day of departure, it will be your responsibility to reconfirm all your flight details before departure. You should always be at the airport 3 hours prior to departure to ensure that you arrive on time for check-in and not miss your flight. No refund is made for unused travel services or any portion thereof, nor is the price or value of unused travel services exchangeable for alternative arrangements. Changes to the current booking are subject to the TERMS AND CONDITIONS as per the TOUR OPERATOR/AIRLINE and as stipulated in the brochure or Airline websites. You are encouraged to purchase the appropriate travel coverage. All purchases, once confirmed are 100% Non-Refundable/Non-Changeable. 

### Cancellation / Changes:

If you need to change or cancel your travel plans, it is your responsibility to notify us immediately by phone of such a request however, please note that the vast majority of our tickets are automatically issued at the time that the reservation is made and are non-refundable. Often times, once a ticket is issued there are certain airlines that will not allow changes or cancellations, and for others, fees from both the airline as well as Flight Network will apply. You should assume all reservations are non-refundable and non-changeable the moment you make the booking. In addition to any change penalties, you will also be responsible for any difference in price for the new dates selected. Furthermore, each ticket has a minimum and maximum stay validity. Minimum stays can range from 2 nights to 14 nights and maximum stays can range from 30 days to 12 months, depending on the type of ticket sold. Changes will not be permitted where the length of the ticket is less than the minimum stay or more than the maximum stay period allotted. Partially used tickets become 100% non-refundable even if only one segment of the ticket is used. Tickets can also not be used out of sequence, meaning that if you miss your first flight you can not catch your second flight. If the first flight is missed, you will forfeit the entire ticket with no option for a refund. As the intermediary, Flight Network is bound to each Airline’s Terms and Conditions and have zero control over their advertised or contracted fare rules. 

### Security Verification:

When changes or cancellations are requested by a passenger, Flight Network will confirm 2-3 steps to verification which could include: confirming booking confirmation numbers, email addresses, home address, telephone number, credit card on file and/or passenger names. If these steps to verification have been successfully answered by the passenger requesting the change or cancellation, Flight Network will complete the request for the passenger. 

### Name Changes / Corrections:

If the tickets have been issued‚ please note name changes and corrections are not permitted. Once the tickets have been issued and if permitted by the airline‚ an additional fee will be assessed by FlightNetwork® and the airline directly. Customers who do not appear or ‘no show’ for their flight will forfeit the entire fare paid. If you arrive at the airport late or are denied boarding you will forfeit the entire fare paid. 

    * Check-In Terms

### Check-in / Boarding times:

We recommend that passengers allow plenty of time to check-in and obtain their boarding pass for their scheduled flight. FlightNetwork® will not be responsible for those passengers who check-in past the airline cut off times. Failure to meet check-in times may result in denied boarding, the loss of your assigned seat selection, cancellation of your full booking and the entire fare paid being forfeited with no option of re booking. Please reconfirm check-in cut off times with the airline directly as the suggested timings are guidelines only and are subject to change without notice. 

### Suggested Check in times :

Domestic flights: 90 minutes prior to departure Transborder flights: 120 minutes prior to departure International flights: 180 minutes prior to departure 

    * Children and travel (entry/exit to South Africa)

As of October 1, 2014, parents travelling with children will be asked to produce the child’s unabridged (long form) birth certificate and a [consent letter](http://travel.gc.ca/travelling/children/consent-letter) (if the child is travelling with only one parent). Other requirements may apply to unaccompanied children. Contact the High Commission of South Africa before travelling. Please consult the Government of Canada here for [more information](http://travel.gc.ca/destinations/south-africa). 

    * Confirmation Terms

### Confirmation:

In some circumstances, your booking will provide you with a confirmation number before a ticket has been issued. The booking process is not complete and the fare is subject to change until a ticket is issued. FlightNetwork® is not accountable for any bookings that could not be processed due to inaccurate and/or incomplete credit card verification information, or due to other technical malfunction with internal or external pricing or booking systems, including errors by the airline or the airline reservations system, you will be notified by email of such issue(s). 

### Flight Reconfirmation:

Outbound and return flights must be reconfirmed with the relevant airlines 24 hours prior to the commencement of that leg of the journey unless specifically informed otherwise by that airline. We accept no responsibility for bookings cancelled due to non-compliance with rules set by that particular airline. We also take no responsibility for any flight rescheduling en route. 

    * Credit Card Terms

### Credit Card:

You agree to authorize the ticket issuer to charge your credit card number the amount that is shown as the Grand Total. 

### Appearance of charges on credit cards/Visa Debits:

The amount displayed for an ‘Authorized Transaction’ may be different from what you actually paid, as some merchants require a temporary hold be placed on additional funds. This is a common practice for many other merchants such as: gas stations, restaurants and hotels. The correct amount will display when the transaction is shown as a ‘Posted Transaction’. A delay may occur between the time a transaction is settled and removed from Authorized Transactions, and when it appears in Posted Transactions. Some transactions may appear as both an Authorized and a Posted Transaction until settled. When applying a debit/visa card for payment, and in the event of a cancellation, your funds may be held up to 60days by your financial institution. We strongly recommend an alternative form of payment to avoid any inconveniences. If you are using a foreign or a third party credit card to make your booking, our Back Office Processing Department may contact you by email or telephone to collect more information. Since Flight Network is a Canadian company, passengers using foreign credit cards may be charged a foreign transaction fee and/or currency conversion fee from their financial institute. Also note, this foreign transaction fee and/or currency conversion fee can apply to Canadian credit card holders, if the booking is made with one of our suppliers based in the US or Europe. We do not take any responsibility for foreign transaction fee and/or currency conversion fee. Flight Network is a Canadian website that deals with many international vendors. When we display a vendor booking, using another currency, our website will show the equivalent to Canadian dollar amount. The final amount that settles on your account will depend on the exchange rate that your credit card company is using. In addition, Flight Network does not have any control over the foreign transaction fees charged by certain credit card companies. 

    * Fees 

### OB Ticketing Fees

The Airline ticketing fees, also called OB Fees, are defined and collected by the validating Carrier and charged to the passenger when a ticket is issued in Australia (at first ticket issuance only). These fees can be imposed to cover charges for a specific Form of Payment (credit card) or for other ticketing services. Airline ticketing fees are non-refundable and are collected at time of ticket issuance automatically depending on the itinerary booked. You will see this as a separate additional charge on your statement which can not be determined in advance. As a result, we are unable to notify you the exact amount at time of purchase. 

### Flight Network Booking Fees

Flight Network will often times charge a booking fee on flights to a particular destination. This fee is lumped into the total cost of your booking. By agreeing to the total purchase price of the ticket, you have also agreed to the Flight Network booking fee. This fee is charged by Flight Network (not the airline) in CAD or USD depending on your booking currency. 

    * Flexible Tickets 

Flight Network’s Flexible Ticket provides customers with the option to change the date on their ticket. The Flexible ticket option can only be added and paid for at the time of booking, and cannot be added after. The Flexible ticket product once purchased, starts from the time that the booking is made up until 48 hours before flight departure. Any changes within 48 hours of the flight are not covered under this option. The Flexible ticket option is per person and will only provide coverage for the person holding the ticket. Flexible tickets cannot be purchased for Infant tickets – Infants are exempt from participating in this booking add-on. The Flexible Ticket option covers the service provider and airlines change fees. If the new date requested has no availability in the same class of service which the original ticket was booked on, the difference in fare will be at the travellers own expense. [See Full Terms & Conditions](https://www.flightnetwork.com/en/pages/terms-conditions-flexible-ticket/)

    * Hotels Terms

### Hotels:

Flightnetwork.com does not collect taxes for remittance to applicable taxing authorities. The tax recovery charges on prepaid hotel transactions are a recovery of the estimated transaction taxes (e.g. sales and use‚ occupancy‚ room tax‚ excise tax‚ value added tax‚ etc) that Flightnetwork.com pays to the hotel supplier in connection with your hotel reservation. The Hotel suppliers remit applicable taxes to the applicable taxing jurisdictions. Flightnetwork.com does not act as a co-vendor with the supplier with whom we reserve your travel arrangements. Taxability and the appropriate tax rates vary greatly by location. The actual tax amounts paid to the hotel suppliers may vary from the tax recovery charge amounts‚ depending upon the rates‚ taxability‚ etc. in effect at the time of actual use of the hotel by our customers. 

    * Insurance Terms

### Insurance:

We strongly recommend travel insurance to cover you for cancellation, health, baggage and other losses including out-of-province health insurance, if applicable. For every sale, Flight Network offers the option to purchase travel insurance to cover the customer against any unforeseen circumstances that may occur prior to, during or after your trip. There are different types of insurance policies available and the purchase of insurance is an optional decision to the customer. Insurance policies purchased on FlightNetwork.com will insure passengers up to the sum of $100, $600 or $800 prior to departure, depending on the airline and journey type where applicable. It is the customers’ responsibility to read and familiarize themselves with the travel insurance policy to understand what their purchased travel insurance covers and under what conditions. If the customer wants to make an insurance claim it is their responsibility to contact Flight Network as soon as possible. Insurance policy cancellations or refunds are not available once the reservation has been booked as the live policies are active as soon as the booking is completed. When an Insurance policy is purchased for multiple travellers on a booking, the policy will be sent to the email address provided at the time of booking. Due to Insurance policy regulations, it is the responsibility of the email account holder to forward this policy and it’s accompanying booklet(s) to all travellers on the booking. Please contact us if you require more information regarding travel insurance. 

    * Emergency or Technical Stops

### Emergency or Technical Stops:

On occasion, an airline or airlines on your itinerary may operate certain routes with technical stops. This means that the plane will stop enroute to fill up on fuel or to deplane passengers without prior notification to us. This may also happen in emergency cases for the safety of the passengers and crew members, due to force majeure, technical and/or political issues. We as the travel agency, do not have control of any such circumstances. 

    * Loyalty Programs & Gift Card Terms

### Frequent Flyer Programs:

Almost all of our Airfares allow accumulation of frequent flyer miles. You enter your frequent flyer program and number in our booking process. Your frequent flyer information is sent to the airline once your ticket is issued. 

### Gift Cards:

Not applicable on Transat Holidays and Nolitours bookings. This is a limited time offer and may be withdrawn without prior notice. 

### Coupon Codes:

Any Coupon Codes applied to a reservation will be processed as a refund immediately after booking and will appear on your statement within 2-3 business days. 

### Instant & Honoured Discounts:

Any Instant Discounts or Honoured Discounts applied to a reservation will be processed as a refund immediately after booking and will appear on your statement within 2-3 business days. 

    * Meals and Other Onboard Services

Many carriers are no longer providing meals and other services ( ex. headsets, drinks) free of cost while onboard. It’s the passenger’s responsibility to inquire about this information prior to purchase and make an informed decision about their travel purchase. Flight Network will not be responsible to cover any costs related to the onboard services provided by the carriers. 

    * Passport & Visa Information

Information on entry requirements to your destination can be found using the information below. If you have questions or are unsure of the documentation needed to travel, please contact us prior to booking your trip. A list of worldwide numbers can be found [here.](http://help.flightnetwork.com/customer/portal/emails/new) Entry to another country may be refused even if the required information and travel documents are complete as travel documentation is subject to change. As well, living standards and practices at the destination and the standards and conditions there with respect to the provision of utilities, services and accommodation may differ from those found in Canada. 

### Travelling/Connecting in European Schengen Countries:

Travellers from countries that currently enjoy visa-free travel throughout Europe’s passport-free Schengen zone face having to apply for a document similar to the US ESTA system, as the EU beefs up security checks. The European Travel Information and Authorization System (ETIAS), which could apply to a post-Brexit Britain, will see visitors from 60 ‘visa-waiver’ countries including the US, Canada and Australia having to pay a €5 application fee for the travel document. The authorization, which the European Commission said will take no longer than 10 minutes and described as a “lighter more visitor-friendly regime” than a visa, will be valid for five years and for multiple trips. It will only apply to those 18 and over. Nationals of the visa-free countries will still be able to travel without one but must obtain the authorization prior to travel in the Schengen Area. All nationals of third countries, which have yet not reached a visa-liberalization agreement with the Schengen member states, need to obtain a visa prior of their arrival in Europe.  If you have two connections/stopovers in the Schengen area (for example Mumbai-Vienna-Frankfurt-Chicago or Nairobi-Zurich-Frankfurt-Chișinău), you will be required to get a Schengen Visa to transit or you will get denied boarding. To check whether you need a Schengen Visa to travel to one of the Schengen member countries, [here is the list of countries, citizens of which must apply for a Schengen Visa prior to their travel to the EU](https://www.schengenvisainfo.com/who-needs-schengen-visa/). 

### Passports/Visas/Health Requirements:

Please note that many countries require that your passport be valid for a period of (a minimum) of six months beyond your return date. You should ensure that you meet the passport, visa, affidavit, return/onward ticket, health and other requirements of the countries you wish to visit and those that you transit (even if it is for a plane change). We accept no responsibility if you should be denied boarding or deported for any reason, including your age. Please [check the documentation and/or inoculations](http://www.iatatravelcentre.com/passport-visa-health-travel-document-requirements.htm) needed for your destination(s). For further questions regarding travel documentation please contact Flight Network directly. Our office is open 24/7 for your convenience. Obtaining passports and visas may require lengthy processing times and entry to another country may be refused even if your required information and travel documents are complete. We accept no responsibility if you should be denied boarding or deported for any reason including your age. You, the customer must be eighteen years of age (please note the restrictions below with respect to children travelling alone to Europe). If you are purchasing travel services for a customer that is not the age of majority in the applicable jurisdiction you must contact our call centre to arrange the purchase. For further questions regarding travel documentation please contact Flight Network directly. Our office is open 24/7 for your convenience. 

### Australian Visa:

If you’ve made a reservation with Flight Network, traveling to Australia, you will likely need a Visa. The type of Visa depends on your circumstances (I.e. length of stay, purpose of visit etc.). Please click[ here](http://www.immi.gov.au/Visas/Pages/Find-a-visa.aspx) to find out what type of Australian Visa you’ll need for your trip. 

### India E-Tourist Visa for International Travelers:

Visit <https://indianvisaonline.gov.in/visa/tvoa.html> to get more information on tourist visas to India and to submit your online applications. 

### Indian Passport Holders:

Please ensure that you hold the proper documentation when your itinerary has a connection via USA. You MUST hold a ‘multiple-entry visa’. If proper documentation is not provided at the time of check-in, the airline reserves the right to deny boarding and the entire ticket cost will be forfeited. 

### European Union Passports:

Passengers travelling to Belgium, the Czech Republic, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, the Netherlands, Portugal, Spain and Switzerland require a passport that must be valid for at least three (3) months beyond the expected date of return. Passengers without valid travel documents will be refused boarding or entry into the destination country. Other countries have similar requirements. For all destinations, it is the responsibility of passengers to ensure that they possess the necessary travel documents. 

### Entry Requirements For United States:

The department of Homeland Security of the United States of America has introduced new laws effective January 23, 2007 governing the entry requirements to the United States by air. These new laws include mandatory passports for all travelers including Canadian and American citizens. Please ensure that your passport is valid for at least 6 months past your desired return date to ensure that there are not any delays in regards to US Immigration. Please take the time to review the website link for the Department of Homeland Security at: <http://www.dhs.gov/crossing-us-borders> For additional information on Canada – U.S. border regulations, please refer to the Canada Border Services Agency website at: <http://www.cbsa-asfc.gc.ca/> If you have any questions about this, please do contact us and we will explain this further for you. 

### For Travel to the following countries, Passports must be:

Valid at least 1 month beyond your return date | Valid at least 3 months beyond your return date | Valid at least 6 months beyond your return date  
---|---|---  
Cayman Islands | Aruba | Barbados  
Colombia | Italy | Belize  
Cuba | Portugal | Brazil  
Jamaica | Spain | Greece  
Mexico | Costa Rica | Haiti  
Trinidad & Tobago | Germany | Honduras  
UK | France | India  
USA |  | Israel  
|  | Liberia  
|  | Margarita Island  
|  | Panama  
|  | Saint Kitts and Nevis  
|  | San Andres  
|  | Turks and Caicos  
|  | Venezuela  
  
    * Price Drop Protection

### Price Drop Protection

Upon redemption, any Price Drop Protection Dollars will be refunded in the form of a cheque and mailed to the credit card holders mailing address on file. Please allow 7-10 days for delivery. To view the full Terms & Conditions of our Price Drop Protection program please visit [this page](https://www.flightnetwork.com/price-drop-protection/terms.shtml). 

    * Samsung Note 7 Banned from most Aircrafts

### Samsung Note 7 Banned from most Aircrafts

Passengers and flight crews will be banned from bringing Samsung Galaxy Note 7 smartphones on all airline flights under emergency orders issued by both Transport Canada and the U.S. Department of Transportation in response to reports of the phones catching fire. The phones may not be carried on board or packed in checked bags on flights to and from Canada and the United States or within either country. The phones also can’t be shipped as air cargo. Passengers with the phones will not be allowed to board planes. And those who try to evade the U.S. ban by packing the phones in checked luggage may be subject to criminal prosecution in addition to fines. Transport officials in both countries warned that carrying the phones in checked luggage increases the potential danger to the flight. The U.S. Consumer Product Safety Commission says there have been nearly 100 reports of batteries in Note 7 phones overheating in the United States. 

    * Seat Selection

Not all tickets offer free seat selection. Some seats can be selected free of cost during online check-in within 24 hours of departure time and some seats require a fee to be paid to the airline. Each airline has a different policy on seat selection. Please verify this information prior to purchase. Seat selection requests at time of booking are not guaranteed and are non-refundable. The airline has full rights to amend any seat selection without prior notice. If a voluntary change is made to a booking, any previously purchased seat selections are not guaranteed to be transferred to new flights. If a flight booking is voluntarily canceled, seat selection requests are non-refundable. Flight Network charges a nominal service charge to select seats for your booking, you will be notified of the amount at time of purchase. 

    * Self-Transfer Guarantee

### Self-transfer Guarantee

“Self-transfer guarantee” is an exclusive policy designed to assist those passengers that are impacted by an involuntary schedule change, delay or cancellation of their confirmed flight resulting from factors, which can occur in the standard course of air transportation. With the implementation of this policy (Self-transfer guarantee), we can offer our customers the best possible price and service experience in the travel industry. We strive to make your journey as smooth and comfortable as possible. Upon activation of this policy, in the event of an involuntary schedule change or cancellation, we shall find you a reasonable alternative flight option(s) or other means of transportation to your destination, or a refund of the unused flight portion. All passengers should be in contact with Flight Network and not the airline in order to be covered under this policy. This policy covers two categories depending on the urgency of your file. 

### Category 1: ( Where the schedule change takes place more than 48 hours prior to departure)

This option applies ONLY if the schedule change (Flight change, or cancellation) takes place outside of 48 hours prior to the first leg of your confirmed itinerary, which prevents you from reaching your final destination, or your arrival in destination is delayed by more than 24 hours after the original arrival time i.e. you would either miss your connecting flight(s) or your flight(s) is cancelled. If you become aware of the schedule change under Category 1, you must get in touch with us immediately without delay either by telephone, email or via our online chat platform found on our website. If you fail to contact us in a timely manner, you will not be covered under this guarantee. If we become aware of the change first, under category 1, we will get in touch with you within a reasonable time. Once we are informed of the change or cancellation either by you or the airline, at our discretion, we will offer you one of the following resolutions: ● We will find you an alternative transportation to your destination. If we can’t re-protect you with the same carrier, we will offer you an alternative flight(s) or other means of transportation to your destination entirely at our cost. In case of lack of availability, and no alternative can be offered and once we are in a **mutual agreement** , you can purchase the similar ticket at the airport in the same cabin class and we will refund you the price difference between the two tickets. Any other extra services or upgrades related to these new tickets will not be covered under this policy. ● For all unused portions, we will refund you accordingly. This option will be offered in case we fail to offer you an alternative transportation. The options will be communicated to you via phone or email. You are obligated to respond to us promptly in ALL cases within the 24 hours of receiving our options. Once the **24 hour** offer period is over, our options become **null and void** and you will not be entitled to our guarantee. 

### Category 2: ( where the schedule change takes place within 48 hours prior to departure)

This option applies ONLY if the schedule change (Flight change, or cancellation) takes place within 48 hours of departure prior to the first leg of your confirmed itinerary, which prevents you from reaching your final destination, or your arrival in destination is delayed by more than 24 hours after the original arrival time i.e. you would either miss your connecting flight(s) or your flight(s) is cancelled If you become aware of the schedule change under Category 2, you must get in touch with us immediately without delay either by **telephone, email or via our online chat** platform found on our website. If you fail to contact us immediately, you will not be covered under this guarantee. If we become aware of the change first under category 2, we will get in touch with you within a reasonable time. Once we are informed of the change or cancellation either by you or the airline, we will offer you one of the following resolutions at your discretion: ● We will find you an alternative transportation to your destination. If we can’t re-protect you with the same carrier, we will offer you an alternative flight(s) or other means of transportation to your destination entirely at our cost. In case of lack of availability, and/or substantial fare difference and once we are in a **mutual agreement** , we will refund you the full amount of your original ticket(s) with us. We may offer to cover part of the costs associated with this change upon a mutual agreement on a case by case basis. In rare cases where you miss the connecting flight or the flight cancellation occurs and you are unable to contact us due to time restriction, you may purchase the ticket without prior agreement with us. We will refund you the price of such alternative transportation ticket(s) upto twice the value of the original ticket price of the unused portion to your destination. Any other extra services or upgrades related to these new tickets will not be covered under this policy. We will only refund you once we are in receipt of the written documentation proof of the alternative transportation and the proof of flight delay or cancellation. The options will be communicated to you via phone or email. You are obligated to respond to us promptly in ALL cases within the 24 hours of receiving our options or well in advance of the scheduled departure time whichever is earlier. Once the 24 hour offer period is over, our options become **null and void** and you will not be entitled to our guarantee. **Flight Network Additional services:** These additional services may be applied to category 2 scenarios under our Self-transfer guarantee. These additional services must be prearranged with our Customer care team in order to have a legitimate claim because they are solely offered at our discretion. The costs associated with these services have to be paid upfront by yourself and then claimed after the fact with valid proof ( transaction receipts). On the basis of such receipts, we will refund the costs upto the amounts listed below. **Overnight Hotel accommodation-** This option is available to you if you are left stranded at the airport for the night and/or your alternative connecting flight is scheduled 8 or more hours later. This overnight is only covered if you have accepted our option with 8 or more hours of delay. In some cases, you will have to book the hotel room locally and claim a refund of $75 CAD per person up to two nights. If additional nights are required due to lack of availability with the airline for an alternative, it must be mutually arranged in advance with Flight Network. **Alternative Transportation:** In cases where all the flights are sold out for the same day, we may cover the costs to book you to depart from other airports in the area in order to get you to your destination at the earliest. This has to be prearranged with Flight Network. The alternative methods can also be a train, coach bus or a taxi and will apply to all the passengers booked on the same reservation. The maximum claim limit for this is $150 CAD; inclusive of all passengers. **Meal and Beverage compensation:** This is covered only if your flight connection is delayed by more than 4 hours. In such cases, we will cover upto $15 CAD per person booked on the itinerary. **Multiple destination routes:** If the itinerary is impacted in a way, where the remaining segments on the same ticket are all impacted and we are unable to find a suitable alternative and the ticket is fully unused, then a refund for all flights on that ticket can be applied. **Communication and notices:** Once we provide you with alternative options, your response is due back to us within 48 hours the **latest** in **exceptional cases**. If the 48 hour window is passed, the offer becomes null and void and is no longer covered under this guarantee. ***If you are offered the above mentioned alternatives by the airline(s) directly or at the airport, we cannot be held responsible for any further compensation or reimbursement. 

### Late Check-in’s / No Shows

Flight Network is not responsible for any late check-ins that occur due to non-compliance with individual airline check-in guidelines for any segments within the confirmed itinerary. Connecting times for each segment of your flight should be taken very seriously. This should always be top of mind, especially when you may need to collect and re-check bags with a new airline. If Flight Network determines (based on the information provided by the operating carriers/booking systems) that the passenger has had sufficient connecting time (even after a delayed arrival), the self-transfer guarantee will not apply. Any related costs will become the passenger’s responsibility in any such cases. 

    * Special Requests

Customers with special needs should contact the operating airline directly for their seating needs. Special requests are on request basis and are not guaranteed. The passengers need to contact the airlines directly to reconfirm such requests. Please be aware that Norwegian Airlines Special Request Policy does not accept Meal Requests within 72 hours of departure. 

    * STPC Charges – Kuwait Airport

Please be informed as per Kuwait DGCA requirements, any passengers who’s transit time exceeds more than 08 hours at Kuwait airport will require to stay at the Safir Airport Hotel which is located inside the airport premises. The passengers will have to cover the cost of this hotel accommodation on their own. Our agents will quote you the fare once requested. 

    * Support Package Terms

Support Package tiers are offered for purchase at the time of booking and cannot be purchased after the reservation has already been made. Once a purchase has been made, the full package inclusions and how to contact us will be provided in the booking confirmation email. Customers must contact us via the explicit instructions in the email otherwise they may not be serviced by the correct department. In the event of a voluntary cancellation, this support option service is non-refundable. 

    * Travel Advisories

Before purchasing a trip with us, please ensure that you’ve checked your destination for any travel advisories that may affect your choice to purchase. Click [here](https://travel.gc.ca/travelling/advisories) for information on travel advisories. 

    * Travel Tax & Airport Fees 

### Argentina

If you are travelling to this country they do impose a “reciprocity’ fee. For more information or to purchase online in advance, please visit [https://www.ivisa.com/visa-argentina-reciprocity-fee.](https://www.ivisa.com/visa-argentina-reciprocity-fee)

### Philippines

Philippine Nationals are expected to pay for the Philippine Travel Tax upon departure from the Philippines. It is usually paid at the airport upon departure or; oftentimes, already included in the cost of the ticket when purchased. US Nationals and Permanent Residents (Green Card Holders) are exempt from the Philippine Travel Tax. US Permanent Residents need to secure a Travel Tax Exemption Certificate from the Philippine Tourism Authority at the Department of Tourism Building at TM Kalaw Street, Ermita Manila. The Philippine Travel Tax is PHP1,620.00 (approximately $35.00). All passengers departing from the NAIA (Ninoy Aquino International Airport) are expected to pay the Airport Terminal Fee of PHP750.00 (approximately $17.00). No one is exempt from paying the Airport Terminal Fee. 

    * Travel to Cuba from USA

When you book or check in for your flight, you will be asked to certify the reason for your visit. There are currently two ways to gain permission to travel to Cuba: with a general license or with a specific license.   If you meet the regulations and conditions of a general license, you will not need to apply for a specific license. There are 13 categories of general licenses related to Cuba travel: 

### 12 permitted purposes include:

– Family visits – Official government business – Journalistic activity – Professional research or meetings – Educational activities or people-to-people exchanges – Religious activities – Sports and public events – Support for the Cuban people – Humanitarian projects – Research – Informational materials – Authorized export activities – Non-immigrant Cuban National You will not qualify for a general license if the reason for your travel is not listed above, and you will be required to apply for a specific license from the U.S. Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC). All license applications are reviewed on a case-by-case basis. Please see the U.S. Department of the Treasury’s OFAC FAQ page for more information. 

    * Travel to Venezuela

As of March 6, 2015, Venezuela (VE) has imposed a visa requirement for all U.S. citizens traveling to VE. All customers in possession of a U.S. passport traveling to VE are required to obtain a visa for air travel to Venezuela, including those born in VE. 

    * Trip Cancellation Protection Terms

### Trip Cancellation Protection:

This program covers the non-refundable portion of the ticket and extras such as baggage costs and set costs, only when these extras have been booked at the time of purchase with Flight Network. Trip Cancellation Protection is not an insurance product. Unfortunately, cancellations/refunds are not available for Trip Cancellation as soon as the booking is completed. 

    * Unaccompanied Minors Terms

### Unaccompanied minors:

It is the customer’s responsibility to read and familiarize themselves in regards to children travelling unaccompanied without an adult over the age of 18 years. Please verify the unaccompanied minor rules and restrictions with the operating airline(s) prior to confirming your booking online. The specific unaccompanied minor service requirements vary from one airline to another. If you fail to meet these requirements, children will be denied boarding and will forfeit the entire fare paid. Please note that flights booked may be code share with other airlines therefore the operating carrier’s rules and regulations will apply. FlightNetwork® will not be held responsible for any fees or passengers denied boarding due to the non compliance of the airlines rules and regulations regarding unaccompanied minors. 

### Travelling to the UK via Air Transat (TS), Thomas Cook (TCX) and MY Travel Airways (MYT).

Please note that the following restrictions have been put in place as of April 27, 2007 in regards to children travelling alone into Europe: For Air Transat Flights – Children will be accepted between the ages of 5 and 11 years of age For Thomas Cook Flights – Children will be accepted only above the age of 16. For My Travel Airways Flights – Children will be accepted only above the age of 16. 

    * US Policy: Passports Issued in Middle Eastern & African Countries

### Effective Jan 27, 2017:

Effective immediately, guests travelling with a passport issued from Iran, Iraq, Sudan, Somalia, Syria, Yemen or Libya are prohibited from entering or transiting the United States for at least 90 days on Immigrant and Non-immigration visas issued in these passports have been revoked. Please contact your local U.S. Embassy if you require any additional information. All airlines are following suit to adhere to the above new government policy. 

    * US/UK Policy: Devices Banned on Aircrafts

### Electronic Device Ban:

The US and UK have moved to ban electronic devices larger than a mobile phone from cabins on flights from some Middle Eastern and North African countries. The new security measures will mean that electronic items and devices larger than a mobile phone will be required to be carried in checked luggage only, not in the main cabin in hand luggage. This will apply to (but is not limited to), laptops, tablets, portable DVD players, cameras, e-readers and gaming devices larger than a smartphone. The policy will come into effect on Friday 24 March 2017 and will impact flights travelling to the United States and the United Kingdom from the following list of countries. 

### The US policy has banned large electronic devices on flights from the following countries:

      * Jordan
      * Egypt
      * Turkey
      * Saudi Arabia
      * Kuwait
      * Qatar
      * Morocco
      * United Arab Emirates

### The UK’s policy, is slight less restrictive and applies to flights from the following countries:

      * Turkey
      * Lebanon
      * Jordan
      * Egypt
      * Tunisia
      * Saudi Arabia

Emirates, Etihad Airways, British Airways and Qatar Airways have advised us directly that the new policy will be in place on their flights from the affected list of countries into the US and UK. The new regulations will affect passengers transiting through the listed countries on to destinations in the US or UK and they will need to check in all prohibited devices before departing Australia. For more information on the UK policy click [here](https://www.gov.uk/government/speeches/additional-airline-security-measures-on-some-routes-travelling-to-the-uk). For more information on the US policy click [here](https://www.dhs.gov/news/2017/03/21/fact-sheet-aviation-security-enhancements-select-last-point-departure-airports). 

    * Vacation Package Terms

### Vacation Package:

By completing a Flight Network Vacation booking you have confirmed that you have read, understand and agreed to the following: 1. All prices quoted herein are based on the supplier(s) system and are quoted in Canadian Dollars. 2. I confirm that the spelling of all passengers names listed above are correct and correspond to the names listed on the Passport (initials are not acceptable). Please ensure the date(s) of birth; destination(s), departure dates, and hotel information are also correct. I understand that if any changes are required after this booking is made, supplier imposed charges will apply. 3. I also agree that it is my responsibility to ensure that I/we have the appropriate documentation (Passport/Visa/ID card etc.) to gain entry to the chosen destination and for re-entry upon return. For Travel outside Canada, please ensure you have a valid passport at least 6 months beyond your return date for all the passengers on file. You may also require a visa depending on the country you are visiting and your passport’s country of issue. 4. Prices, availability, and dates during this period are subject to change as per the supplier(s) rules and regulations. 5. Changes and/or Cancellations may result in a 100% penalty as per supplier terms and conditions plus any applicable administration fee(s). 6. Airlines may apply additional fees for items such as checked baggage. Be sure to confirm any applicable fees with the airline or Tour Operator directly. 7. Flight Network does not assume any liability for cancelled flights, flights that are missed, or flights not connecting due to any schedule changes made by the airlines. 8. Guests must check-in 3 hours prior to the scheduled departure time. Passports and proper travel documents will be required for check in purposes. Please contact your local Embassy and airline for proper documents required, it is YOUR responsibility to ensure you have all travel documents and Visas required for entry into the traveling country. Guests arriving less than 1.5 hour prior to the scheduled departure will be denied boarding. 9. Purchases made with a third party credit cards(the use of a credit card that does not belong to any of the passengers on file, will be required to show the credit card to the airline and/or tour operator at time of check in. If the credit card is not presented, you may be required to purchase a new ticket at your own cost. Flight Network reverses the right to request proof of documents (back and front of card and copy of driver’s license/passport) for bookings using a third party credit card. 10. Once the Purchase Now button is pressed, an email will be sent with additional information on how to retrieve your tickets/e-document for your travel plans. Please read this email carefully before contacting Flight Network. If a per person processing fee is applicable, this amount has been added to your price and charged by Flight Network and separate charges may show on your credit card statement. 11. All reservations are not guaranteed until ticketed or the Booking Status says CONFIRMED/OK. 12. For full terms and conditions, please refer to the terms and conditions from the Suppliers Brochure or Airline website. 13. By submitting your transaction online, you authorize Flight Network to process this reservation with the supplier(s) on your behalf. Please note the cost of your package will be charged to your credit card directly by the supplier(s). Additional departure taxes or airport fees may be applicable. 14. Prices include all transportation taxes, fuel surcharges, GST, and PST. Any local taxes or charges payable to a third party in destination are not included in the total price shown. 15. For Québec residents, prices do not include the client’s contribution to the Indemnity Fund, amounting to $1 per $1,000 of travel services purchased. Indemnity Fund charges will be added to your invoice and charged to your credit card separately. *** Note: Flight times and date changes may occur from time to time based on suppliers provided information. Once received, Flight Network will provide this information via email provided in the booking. Please ensure you check your emails for any additional information.**

### Vacation e-documents:

Please [click here](https://www.flightnetwork.com/etickets/) for information about e-documents available by specific Tour Operators. Please ensure that you contact the Airline directly at least 24 hours prior to the date of your flight for any schedule changes that may have occurred and to reconfirm your flight departure times. For information in regards to your terminal and your flight reconfirmation number please visit your local airport authority for the airline phone number and departure terminals. Please ensure you are at the airport at least 3 hours prior to departure, as Flight Network will not be responsible for missed flights. 

### Price Drop Protection – Vacations

Click [here](https://www.flightnetwork.com/price-drop-protection/faq.shtml) for details on Price Drop Protection on Vacations 

We are required and would be pleased to answer any questions that you may have concerning the foregoing. Flight Network records all calls for quality assurance and training purposes. 

#### Use of Site

You may only use this site to make legitimate inquiries or registration and shall not use this site to make any speculative, false or fraudulent statement in anticipation of collection information not generally available to the travel trade. 

#### Online Fare Reservations, Misprints, and Product Availability

In the event that more than one set of conditions apply to the same trip then the most restrictive conditions of both sets apply to the entire journey. While it is possible to make bookings electronically for some of the travel services, the act of reserving a product electronically does not imply a final confirmation or commitment by FlightNetwork® to actually deliver the product reserved at the prices indicated. FlightNetwork®, endeavors to provide current and accurate information on its website, however any misprints or errors may occur. Accordingly FlightNetwork®, reserves the right to change the prices, fees, charges regarding the goods and services available on its website at any time and from time to time without any notice or liability to the user or any other person. Also, FlightNetwork®, cannot guarantee that goods and services advertised on the website may be available when ordered or thereafter FlightNetwork® reserves the right at any time to reject, amend, cancel or terminate any order without prior notification. A final confirmation is only given by FlightNetwork® once the company has issued the airline tickets, a final invoice and delivered travel documents for the product reserved. Terms and conditions of the confirmation and sale will vary depending on the product reserved and are generally set out in the company’s website or other notices issued from time to time. 

This Privacy Policy explains how we collect your personal information on our website, how we protect such information, and the choices you have concerning the use and disclosure of such information. Your privacy is important to Flight Network. Please read the Policy below carefully. At Flight Network, providing a private and secure purchase environment is one of our top priorities. We want you to be as comfortable and at ease as possible when visiting our website. We are dedicated to protecting the privacy of those users who visit and browse our website. Please remember that this Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by our website. We are not responsible for the privacy of any information you reveal or choose to post in any public forum or for the privacy practices of websites that are operated or owned by third parties. 

  * The Type of Information we collect

### What is Personally Identifiable Information?

Personally Identifiable Information (PII) is any piece of information which can potentially be used to uniquely identify, contact, or locate a single person. This includes information like your real name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card number, or other information that you submit to us voluntarily. You can choose not to provide information to us, but in general some information about you is required in order for you to book travel or initiate other transactions on our site. Email and Other Voluntary Communications – You may also choose to communicate with Flight Network through email, via our website, via telephone, in writing, or through any other means. We collect all information in these communications therefore, if you do not want us to obtain any Personally Identifiable Information about you, do not voluntarily submit such information to us. 

### Use of Personally Identifiable Information

Flight Network takes your privacy seriously and will only share and use your Personally Identifiable Information as described in this Privacy Policy.Unless you give us permission to do so, Flight Network will not sell, share, license, trade or rent your Personally Identifiable Information other than as specified under this Privacy Policy. 

### Use of Personally Identifiable Information

Flight Network takes your privacy seriously and will only share and use your Personally Identifiable Information as described in this Privacy Policy.Unless you give us permission to do so, Flight Network will not sell, share, license, trade or rent your Personally Identifiable Information other than as specified under this Privacy Policy 

### Automatic Collection of Non-Personally Identifiable Information

When you visit or browse our website, we may collect information that by itself cannot be used to identify or contact you (“Non-Personally Identifiable Information”). Non-Personally Identifiable Information may also include certain anonymous information about the type of browser you use and the server name through which you access the Internet (such as “sympatico.com” or “rogers.com”), the date and time you access our website, the pages you access while on our website, and the Internet address of the website, if any, from which you linked directly to our website. Non-Personally Identifiable Information is used to help us understand the characteristics of people who visit our website and to improve and market our website in general. In the event that we link any Non-Personally Identifiable Information with Personally Identifiable Information, we will treat such information as Personally Identifiable Information and only use such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

  * Information We Use

### Information We Use

Flight Network may use the Personally Identifiable Information collected through our website primarily for such purposes as: providing services and support to users; improving our website, including tailoring it to users’ preferences; responding to users’ questions, inquiries, comments and instructions; maintaining the security and integrity of our systems. In general, we use the Personally Identifiable Information collected on our website to enable you to make travel reservations and other travel related online purchases. When you make a reservation or purchase online with FlightNetwork®, we will share information about you and your purchase with the applicable travel suppliers. We will only provide the necessary information to ensure your travel arrangements are confirmed with these travel suppliers. The travel suppliers will use your credit-card information to process your ticket or reservation. We also use the Non-Personally Identifiable Information collected automatically by our servers internally primarily to help us administer and improve our website. Your PII will be retained as required for fulfillment of our legal rights and obligations, as described to you at the point of collection or otherwise until the purpose for which it was collected has been fulfilled. 

  * How we Disclose the information we collect

### Disclosure of Information

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, we will not disclose any information we gather from you on our website. Any and all the information collected on our website will be kept strictly confidential and will not be sold, shared, licensed, traded, rented, or loaned. Any information you give us will be held with the utmost care. If you have any questions, please feel free to contact our privacy officer at the telephone number or address set out below. 

### Affiliates

We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information about you to our Affiliates. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, “Affiliates” means any person or entity which directly or indirectly controls, is controlled by or is under common control with Flight Network, whether by ownership or otherwise. Any information relating to you that we provide to our Affiliates will be treated by those Affiliates in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 

### Laws and Legal Rights

We may also disclose your Personally Identifiable Information if we believe in good faith that we are required to do so in order to comply with any applicable statute, regulation, rule or law, a subpoena, a search warrant, a court or regulatory order, or other valid legal process. We may disclose Personally Identifiable Information in special circumstances when we have reason to believe that providing such information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against a third party who may be violating our terms & conditions, or to protect the safety and/or security of our users, our website and/or the general public. 

### Third Parties Generally

WWe may provide to third parties, information about you that may or may not allow you to be identified or contacted, including where such information is combined with similar information of other users of our website. Third party vendors may have access to and may collect information needed to perform their functions and are not permitted to share or use the information for any other purpose. For instance, we may provide information to third parties regarding the number of unique users who visit our website, the demographic breakdown of the registered users of our website, the necessary data to complete transactions or the activities that visitors to our website engage in while on our website. The third parties to which we may provide this information may include potential or actual commercial or deal partners, sponsors, licensees, researchers and other similar parties. 

### Third-Party Sites

Flight Network will not sell any of your personal information, including your name, address, credit-card number, shopping, or transaction history to any third party without your permission. 

### Data storage outside of Canada

Please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in countries other than Canada. For example, cloud infrastructure may be located in another country. The data protection and other laws of these other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred outside of Canada and to those third parties with whom we share it as described in this Privacy Policy. 

### Outside Contractors

We may employ independent contractors, vendors and suppliers (collectively, “Outside Contractors”) to provide specific services and products related to our website. These Outside Contractors may sometimes have limited access to information collected on our website, including your Personally Identifiable Information, in the course of providing products or services to us. Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these Outside Contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary in order for the Outside Contractors to perform their limited function for us. We also require that these Outside Contractors (i) protect the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, and (ii) not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with the products or services for which we contracted. 

  * Privacy Policies Related to Technology

### Email Communications

We want to make the experience for you as easy as possible when visiting our website. One of the ways that we do this is with communication through email. We believe our email messages will provide you with useful information about travel-related special offers available through our website. You always have the option to choose not to receive any of our email communications via an unsubscribe link in each and every mailing. This way you control the emails that you do and do not wish to receive from us. Flight Network will only mail to those who have opted-in to be mailed to or those that have transacted with us using our website. If you have chosen to unsubscribe to our email mail list, we will cease all sends within 10 days of your original request. Please note that during this 10 day period you may or may not receive another email send from us. Once you have unsubscribed from any email send Flight Network must receive an explicit request from you to re-subscribe before we can send any future email communications to you. Each of Flight Network’s email communications includes a relevant subject line, our full company name, our postal address, IATA number and an easy method of contacting us at any time. 

### What kind of emails do we send?

We send a variety of email communications to our customers. If you have recently searched for a flight, we may send an email related to that product you have searched, along with other products and services that we think may be of interest to you. If you complete a purchase with us, we will send you an email confirming that purchase and three days post purchase up until the time you travel, we may send a reconfirmation email to recap your flight details which may or may not include alternate products pertaining to your travel destination or that we feel may be of interest. You may receive email communications 2-4 times weekly. When opting in to any of our email publications you may receive a welcome or thank you email from us confirming your participation. An example of this would include subscribing to our weekly Top Deals Newsletter. We may send you an email regarding any Flight Network Price Drop Protection communication which may or may not include periodic updates on balances, new credits earned, expiration notices or travel products or services that we feel may be of interest to you. We also help to keep you informed about our travel related products by sending emails on your specific travel related interests. For example if you search for a flight to Vancouver, begin the booking process but do not complete your booking with us, we may send an email notice to serve as a reminder that you have recently began a booking on our website and that we can continue to help you complete it. We may also send an email offering a nearby hotel or car rental to package with a flight that you have already purchased. You may receive these types of email communications if (a) you are a My Flight Network Account holder and abandon a search from our website (b) you click from any one of our Flight Network emails, return back to our site and abandon a search or (c) you input your email address when attempting to confirm a booking and abandon your search. All customers that complete a booking on the Flight Network website will automatically have a My Flight Network Account created. You will receive an email opt-in confirmation and once confirmed, an additional email welcoming you to the program outlining features and benefits. Upon registering, if you choose to opt-in to our Top Deals weekly publication you will also receive a welcome email indicating your subscription confirmation. If you are the Main Account holder of a My Flight Network Account you may receive an email on your birthday if the information is provided to Flight Network at the time of registration or any time thereafter. 

### Advertising within email communications

We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services. No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> Additionally, emails we send may contain a bit of code known as a “web beacon.” This code allows us to understand the time and date of when a user has opened an email and when he/she has utilized a link within the email to visit a website. Our web beacons do not collect personally identifiable information. Users wishing to disable our web beacons should do so by turning images “off” in their email client (e.g., Outlook, Gmail). Please see your email client for more information. 

### My FlightNetwork® Accounts

When registered for a My Flight Network Account you can: choose not to provide us with any or all of your personal travel information or preferences such as preferred seating, special meal requests and frequent flyer numbers. However, providing this information will assist in faster checkouts and may be required to take advantage of certain features offered through this program. The user may add personal travel information or preferences for friends of family and delete these travelers at any time. The option to unsubscribe to our commercial messages is available at any time. Contact us via the Account Help link at any time with questions on your MyFlight Network Account. View current and past flight bookings made with us. View your past search history made on our website. Update your email address, name and password at any time. Take advantage of Price Drop Protection on products to which it is offered. We reserve the right to send you other email communications that are service related and may include service-type information, administrative communications relating to your My Flight Network Account or to the transactions you make on our website. These publications are not considered commercial and do not offer you the opportunity to opt-out or unsubscribe. 

### Sale of Business

We reserve the right to disclose and/or transfer information (including your Personally Identifiable Information) to a third party in the event of a proposed or actual sale, merger or other transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of Flight Network, provided that the third party agrees to adhere to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

### Cookies

Cookies are information stored on your computer. Cookies in some cases are used to track your movement for the sole purpose of remarketing based on your personal search preferences. We also use cookies throughout our site to (a) remember what cities and dates you previously searched for flight information to be able to better offer you a personalized on-site experience, and (b) automatically log you into your My Flight Network account (c) tailor certain advertisements to your browser that we think may be of interest to you or (d) determine the popularity of certain content on our website. The advertisements you see on this website are served by us or by our service providers. Third parties, such as our business partners and ad networks, may be allowed to collect information about the activities of users of our website through cookies and other technologies. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about characteristics, interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the internet that are tailored to your actions. Although you do not have to accept cookies to use our website, you may not be able to use certain resources of our website if you choose not to accept cookies. Although most browsers are initially set to accept cookies, you may reset your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie or to reject cookies generally. Note that if you choose not to receive tailored ads, you will still see online advertisements, but they will be more general and not tailored to online behavioral information about you. Most browsers offer instructions on how to do so in the “Help” section of the toolbar. 

### Third-Party Sites

Flight Network will not sell any of your personal information, including your name, address, credit-card number, shopping, or transaction history to any third party without your permission. Please be aware that our site contains links to other sites and that the privacy practices of other sites may differ from those of Flight Network. In certain situations, you may link to another site within a Flight Network frame that shows a Flight Network URL. In these cases Flight Network makes all reasonable efforts to confirm the security and privacy practices of these sites, but despite the Flight Network frame and URL, each site is responsible for its own privacy practices. 

  * Flight Network’s Accessible Service Policy

### Intent

Flight Network strives at all times to provide goods and/or services in a way that respects the dignity and independence of persons with disabilities. This policy is available in alternate formats upon request. 

### This policy is available in alternate formats upon request.

#### Practice

###### Communication:

Flight Network employees will communicate to persons with disabilities in ways that take into account their disability. 

###### Training:

Flight Network will ensure that all employees who interact with our customers and other third parties receive training as required by the Accessibility Standards for Customer Service. In addition, training will be provided to our employees as part of orientation training for new employees and on a continuing basis as required, such as when changes are made to our Accessible Customer Service Policy. Training will include: 

    * • A review of the purposes of the Accessibility for Ontarians with Disabilities Act, 2005, and the requirements of the Accessibility Standards for Customer Service;
    * • Information about Flight Network’s policies, procedures and guidelines pertaining to the provision of Flight Network’s goods and/or services to customers with disabilities;
    * • How to interact and communicate with persons with various types of disabilities;
    * • What to do if a person with a disability is having difficulty in accessing goods, services or resources;
    * • How to interact with persons with disabilities who use assistive devices or require the assistance of a service animal or a support person;

###### Assistive Devices:

Flight Network is committed to serving persons with disabilities who use assistive devices to obtain, use or benefit from our goods and/or services. While Flight Network and its employees are committed to familiarizing themselves with the various assistive devices that may be used by customers, where an employee is not immediately able to service the customer via the assistive device he/she uses, that employee will immediately refer the matter to Stuart Baum, CHRO (stuart.baum@flightnetwork.com), who will be vested with the responsibility to achieve the necessary customer service to that customer via that assistive device as quickly as reasonably possible. 

###### Use of Service Animals and Support Persons:

Flight Network is committed to serving persons with disabilities who use assistive devices to obtain, use or benefit from our goods and/or services. Persons with disabilities may bring their service animal on the parts of our premises that are open to our customers or other third parties, and the animal is not otherwise excluded by law. Flight Network will ensure that all employees, including volunteers and third parties, dealing with customers are trained in how to interact with persons with disabilities who are accompanied by a service animal. It is the responsibility of the person with a service animal to control the animal at all times. In the event an employee is allergic to animals, alternative arrangements will be negotiated. Any person with a disability who is accompanied by a support person will be allowed to enter Flight Network’s premises open to customers or other third parties with his or her support person. At no time will a person with a disability who is accompanied by a support person be prevented from having access to his or her support person while on the Company’s premises. Consent from the person with a disability is required when communicating private issues related to the person with a disability, in the presence of a support person. 

###### Notice of Temporary Disruptions:

Flight Network will make reasonable efforts to provide customers with notice in the event of a planned or unexpected disruption in the facilities or services normally used by persons with disabilities. This notice will include information about the reason for the disruption, how long the disruption is expected to last, and a description of any alternative facilities or services, if available. This notice will be provided in accessible formats and will be displayed prominently on the company’s website. 

###### Feedback Process:

Flight Network welcomes feedback, including feedback in the delivery of goods and/or services to persons with disabilities. Customers can submit feedback to Allison Eberle, Vice President Operations (allison.eberle@flightnetwork.com). Customers can expect to hear back in 72 hours. Complaints will be addressed according to the Company’s regular complaint management procedures. 

###### Modifications to this or Other Policies:

Flight Network is committed to developing customer service policies that respect and promote the dignity and independence of persons with disabilities. Therefore, no change will be made to this policy before considering the impact on persons with disabilities. Any Company policy that does not respect and promote the dignity and independence of persons with disabilities will be modified or removed. 

###### Questions about this Policy:

This policy exists to achieve service excellence to customers with disabilities. If anyone has a question about this policy please contact: Stuart Baum, CHRO at stuart.baum@flightnetwork.com. 

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement page, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis. By using our website, or any of our online products or services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

### How to Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or feel that we are not abiding by the terms of our posted Privacy Policy, please contact our privacy officer **Toll Free** : 1-877-496-4815 **Local** : 905-829-8699 **Fax** : 905 829 9102. 

### Contacting Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada

If you have any questions or concerns about the practice dealings of FlightNetwork®, we would encourage you to contact the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at the following address: Privacy Commissioner of Canada 112 Kent Street Ottawa, Ontario K1A 1H3 Phone: (613) 995-8210 Toll-free: 1-800-282-1376 Fax: (613) 947-6850 www.privcom.gc.ca 

### Find [Discounted flight](https://www.flightnetwork.com/discount-flights/) tickets on all domestic flights.
